<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Pragmatic Programming</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Pragmatic Programming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pawelweselak.com/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up networking between VirtualBox VMs</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vbox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vbox/</guid><description>Networking in VirtualBox Link to heading There are several modes one can use for networking in VirtualBox. In this article I presented one way for network setup. VMs talk each other using internal network separated from host. Additionaly, I created OpnSense router to access VMs in internal network.
To quickly spin desired number of VMs I used VBoxManage CLI utility and Ubuntu VBox cloud image.
Configuration steps Link to heading Install OpnSense Link to heading Follow guide in the referenced article.</description></item><item><title>Lima quick-start</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:50:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</guid><description>Motivation Link to heading Since January 31st, 2022 Docker Desktop cannot be commercially used for free in bigger organisations. Until now several tools may fill the gap, if you, my Dear Developer, forced to uninstall Docker Desktop. Docker Desktop is a complete, self-sufficient package ready to use tools including UI to run containers. To replace Docker Desktop you will need to build a custom setup comprising set of tools. Installing and configuring different tools may be complex and time-consuming.</description></item><item><title>Affordable cloud solutions for programmers</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 17:34:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vps/</guid><description> Introduction Link to heading Results Link to heading CPU performance Link to heading</description></item></channel></rss>