<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>networking on Pragmatic Programming</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in networking on Pragmatic Programming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pawelweselak.com/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Samba server setup on Ubuntu</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/samba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/samba/</guid><description>Carnival is at the height of the season, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to publish the first post in 2024!
Samba is not only popular dance from Brasil and music instrument, but also a unix service.
Typically in a home LAN, you need some interoperability between your linux and windows machines. For instance file sharing between home server and personal computers of the family members. And one of the simplest solutions for that on Linux is&amp;hellip; Yes, you nailed it, Samba!</description></item><item><title>VPN with nmcli on Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router-vpn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router-vpn/</guid><description>In my previous article I described how to setup cellurar networking on RaspberryPi with GSM hat. The problem is most often you will not get public IP address from your operator when using cellurar network. It means difficulties to access to your RaspberryPi and it&amp;rsquo;s network from remote location. On the other hand the device is not exposed to the Internet threats.
In my case I want to use my RPi to control survilance system installed in a holiday cottage.</description></item><item><title>LTE router on Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router/</guid><description>I finally managed to find some free time to take a look on Waveshare SIM7600E-H 4G HAT. I bought it to extend capabilities of my Raspberry Pi 4 model B single board computer.
Here, I want to give a short tutorial how to setup LTE WAN networking in Raspberry Pi SBC. I will describe how to make use of the network tooling in new Raspberry Pi OS which is based on recent Debian Bookworm release.</description></item><item><title>Setting up networking between VirtualBox VMs</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vbox-networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vbox-networking/</guid><description>There are several modes one can use for networking in VirtualBox. In this article I presented one way for network setup. VMs talk each other using internal network separated from the host machine. Additionaly, I created OpnSense router to access VMs in internal network from the host.
To quickly spin desired number of VMs I used VBoxManage CLI utility and Ubuntu VBox cloud image.
Networking in VirtualBox - Photo by Pixabay on Pexels</description></item><item><title>Lima quick-start</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:50:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</guid><description>Motivation Link to heading Since January 31st, 2022 Docker Desktop cannot be commercially used for free in bigger organisations. Until now several tools may fill the gap, if you, my Dear Developer, forced to uninstall Docker Desktop. Docker Desktop is a complete, self-sufficient package ready to use tools including UI to run containers. To replace Docker Desktop you will need to build a custom setup comprising set of tools. Installing and configuring different tools may be complex and time-consuming.</description></item></channel></rss>