<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tools on Pragmatic Programming</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/categories/tools/</link><description>Recent content in tools on Pragmatic Programming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pawelweselak.com/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Samba server setup on Ubuntu</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/samba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/samba/</guid><description>Samba
Install samba Link to heading sudo apt update sudo apt install samba Add samba user for yourself Link to heading sudo smbpasswd -a $USER sudo usermod -a -G sambashare $USER net usershare add priv ~/Documents/priv &amp;#34;My Documents&amp;#34; $USER:f,everyone:d guest_ok=n Edit config Link to heading sudo nano /etc/samba/smb.conf sudo service smbd restart Add accounts for others Link to heading sudo useradd -M -G sambashare karen sudo passwd -l karen net usershare add documents ~/Documents/shared &amp;#34;Shared Documents&amp;#34; $USER:f,karen:f,everyone:d guest_ok=n Verify users and shares Link to heading sudo pdbedit -L -v net usershare info --long Configure firewall Link to heading sudo ufw allow from 192.</description></item><item><title>Multiple SSH keys setup for git</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/github-multiuser/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/github-multiuser/</guid><description>I always configure git to use SSH for connection. And I don&amp;rsquo;t share private keys among instances. I belive this is the best practice.
As a contractor, I need to perform my work duties on my personal equipment from time to time. Organisations quite often hosts its repositories on github.com.
GitHub in its official docs encourage users to use the same personal account for both private use and when working for an organisation.</description></item><item><title>Lima quick-start</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:50:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</guid><description>Motivation Link to heading Since January 31st, 2022 Docker Desktop cannot be commercially used for free in bigger organisations. Until now several tools may fill the gap, if you, my Dear Developer, forced to uninstall Docker Desktop. Docker Desktop is a complete, self-sufficient package ready to use tools including UI to run containers. To replace Docker Desktop you will need to build a custom setup comprising set of tools. Installing and configuring different tools may be complex and time-consuming.</description></item><item><title>Git cheatsheet</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/git-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/git-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Intro Link to heading During the years of experience with git I have noted aside many commands which could be useful. In this short article I present the most frequently used git commands and configuration steps I always follow in a new work environment.
Configuration Link to heading User information
$ git config --global user.name &amp;quot;Weselak, Pawel&amp;quot; $ git config --global user.email &amp;quot;nospam@pawelweselak.com&amp;quot; SSH keys
$ ssh-keygen -t rsa -b 4096 -C &amp;quot;nospam@pawelweselak.</description></item></channel></rss>