<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Pragmatic Programming</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Pragmatic Programming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pawelweselak.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Make your commits more reliable and secure</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/git-signing-commits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/git-signing-commits/</guid><description>Most probably you are aware of SSH private key authentication mechanism. Recent developments in OpenSSH tooling enable using SSH private keys also for signing. There is a debate if it is right decision to add a new capibility to OpenSSH which was designed for other purpose. Let&amp;rsquo;s leave aside this dispute and just check how we can benefit from SSH signing functionality.
On a daily basis I use SSH for interactions with git repositories.</description></item><item><title>Samba server setup on Ubuntu</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/samba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/samba/</guid><description>Carnival is at the height of the season, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to publish the first post in 2024!
Samba is not only popular dance from Brasil and music instrument, but also a unix service.
Typically in a home LAN, you need some interoperability between your linux and windows machines. For instance file sharing between home server and personal computers of the family members. And one of the simplest solutions for that on Linux is&amp;hellip; Yes, you nailed it, Samba!</description></item><item><title>Multiple SSH keys setup for git</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/github-multiuser/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/github-multiuser/</guid><description>I always configure git to use SSH for connection. And I don&amp;rsquo;t share private keys among instances. I belive this is the best practice.
As a contractor, I need to perform my work duties on my personal equipment from time to time. Organisations quite often hosts its repositories on github.com.
GitHub in its official docs encourage users to use the same personal account for both private use and when working for an organisation.</description></item><item><title>VPN with nmcli on Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router-vpn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router-vpn/</guid><description>In my previous article I described how to setup cellurar networking on RaspberryPi with GSM hat. The problem is most often you will not get public IP address from your operator when using cellurar network. It means difficulties to access to your RaspberryPi and it&amp;rsquo;s network from remote location. On the other hand the device is not exposed to the Internet threats.
In my case I want to use my RPi to control survilance system installed in a holiday cottage.</description></item><item><title>LTE router on Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/rpi-lte-router/</guid><description>I finally managed to find some free time to take a look on Waveshare SIM7600E-H 4G HAT. I bought it to extend capabilities of my Raspberry Pi 4 model B single board computer.
Here, I want to give a short tutorial how to setup LTE WAN networking in Raspberry Pi SBC. I will describe how to make use of the network tooling in new Raspberry Pi OS which is based on recent Debian Bookworm release.</description></item><item><title>Setting up networking between VirtualBox VMs</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vbox-networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/vbox-networking/</guid><description>There are several modes one can use for networking in VirtualBox. In this article I presented one way for network setup. VMs talk each other using internal network separated from the host machine. Additionaly, I created OpnSense router to access VMs in internal network from the host.
To quickly spin desired number of VMs I used VBoxManage CLI utility and Ubuntu VBox cloud image.
Networking in VirtualBox - Photo by Pixabay on Pexels</description></item><item><title>Lima quick-start</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:50:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/lima-vm/</guid><description>Motivation Link to heading Since January 31st, 2022 Docker Desktop cannot be commercially used for free in bigger organisations. Until now several tools may fill the gap, if you, my Dear Developer, forced to uninstall Docker Desktop. Docker Desktop is a complete, self-sufficient package ready to use tools including UI to run containers. To replace Docker Desktop you will need to build a custom setup comprising set of tools. Installing and configuring different tools may be complex and time-consuming.</description></item><item><title>Kotest 4.0 migration guide</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/kotest-migration-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/kotest-migration-guide/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s changed in the new version
Photo by Pixabay on Pexels
Intro Link to heading In the Kotlintest adventures post I described how my team solved different issues faced while implementing test cases in Kotlintest, the testing library for Kotlin. Recently there was a major release of that library. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what has been changed and what steps to take in order to make use of the newest version of the library.</description></item><item><title>Kotlintest adventures</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/kotlintest-adventures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 22:45:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/kotlintest-adventures/</guid><description>Common pitfalls and how to deal with them
Photo by Mateusz Dach on Pexels
Intro Link to heading Our team currently started cruise to develop the next version of ‘the API&amp;rsquo; and a new set of services emerged during that journey. We have a free hand to sail to the open waters of technologies ocean, so we can choose the best fit for our project. Our ship wharfed to an island named Kotlin language.</description></item><item><title>Git cheatsheet</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/git-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/git-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Intro Link to heading During the years of experience with git I have noted aside many commands which could be useful. In this short article I present the most frequently used git commands and configuration steps I always follow in a new work environment.
Configuration Link to heading User information
$ git config --global user.name &amp;quot;Weselak, Pawel&amp;quot; $ git config --global user.email &amp;quot;nospam@pawelweselak.com&amp;quot; SSH keys
$ ssh-keygen -t rsa -b 4096 -C &amp;quot;nospam@pawelweselak.</description></item><item><title>Popular EIP frameworks comparison</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/eip-frameworks-comparison/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/eip-frameworks-comparison/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spring Batch air pollution measurements example</title><link>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/spring-batch-example/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pawelweselak.com/posts/spring-batch-example/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>